Guide to the J. B. Fuqua Papers, 1929-2006 and undated RL.00426
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 2008-0024
  - Home Office Files
    - Oglethorpe University Commencement - May 18, 1986 Address given by: Mr. J.B. Fuqua Tape #3, 1986 (Box 117-119)
      Not reviewed, tape 3.
    - Regarding Fuqua Conservatory Tape #1 Tape, 1989 (Box 117-119)
    - Regarding Fuqua Conservatory Tape #2 Tape, 1989 (Box 117-119)
    - Regarding Fuqua Conservatory Tape #3 Tape, 1989 (Box 117-119)
    - 2nd Show Tape (Box 117-119)
    - Reel #1 Tape (Box 117-119)
    - Reel 1A Tape (Box 117-119)
    - Three (3) copies of ViP JBF March 31 speech to Clayton State College Foundation Trustees Video tape - Event at Clayton State including speech by Fuqua, 1987 (Box 117-119)
    - 3/31/87 CLAYTON STATE COLLEGE Video tape - Event at Clayton State including speech by Fuqua, 1987 (Box 117-119)
      Unprofessional copy of same event above (See item 422).
    - Cumberland College 2002-03 Fuqua Awards Video tape - Award Ceremony for the J.B. Fuqua Excellence in Teaching Awards followed by short monologues by each of the award winners, 2003 (Box 117-119)
    - Fuqua Awards Video tape - Award Ceremony for the J. B. Fuqua Excellence in Teaching Awards followed by a short monologue by each of the award winners, 1998 (Box 117-119)
      Tape includes photograph of the three awardees.
    - Cumberland College 2003-04 Fuqua Awards Video tape - Award Ceremony for the J. B. Fuqua Excellence in Teaching Awards followed by a short monologue by each of the award winners, 2004 (Box 117-119)
    - May 11, 2002 Cumberland College Graduation Fuqua Awards Video tape - Award Ceremony for the J. B. Fuqua Excellence in Teaching Awards followed by a short monologue by each of the award winners, 2002 (Box 117-119)
    - Cumberland College Graduation May 6, 2001 Video tape - Recording of Cumberland's 2001 Graduation Ceremony including the awarding of an honorary Doctorate to Dorothy Fuqua, 2001 (Box 117-119)
      A cursory review show no appearance or speech by Fuqua.
    - Cumberland College Annual Commencement May 6, 2001 Video tape - Recording of Cumberland's 2001 Graduation Ceremony including the awarding of an honorary Doctorate to Dorothy Fuqua, 2001 (Box 117-119)
      Another copy of the ceremony recorded above (See item 434).
    - Cumberland College Video tape - Award Ceremony for the J. B. Fuqua Excellence in Teaching Awards followed by a short monologue by each of the award winners, 2001 (Box 117-119)
      J.B. Fuqua present at ceremony to confer award, but gave no speech on tape.
    - Two (2) copies of Atlanta Business Chronicle Biggest/Best Deals of 1986 Luncheon J.B.F. Video tape - Recording of Ernst & Whinney/Atlanta Business Chronicle Award Luncheon, 1987 (Box 117-119)
      Another copy of award ceremony on tape in box 20 (See item 335).
    - Five (5) Copies of FUQUA CONSERVATORY: Broadcast Clips PSAs WSB-TV: Wild, Fresh & Exotic Dedication Ceremony Video tape - News reports regarding Dorothy Chapman Fuqua Conservatory including a short interview with Dorothy and J.B. Fuqua and footage of the dedication of the Conservatory with a speech by J.B. Fuqua, 1989 (Box 117-119)
      Speech by J.B. Fuqua at dedication ceremony at end of this tape.
    - Two (2) Copies of FUQUA CONSERVATORY: WSB-TV 'Wild, Fresh & Exotic' 3-10-89 Dedication Ceremony, Unedited 3-18-89 Video tape - Recording of program that appeared on Atlanta TV highlighting the new Conservatory (including a short interview with the Fuquas) and footage from the dedication including a short speech by J.B. Fuqua, 1989 (Box 117-119)
      All material on this tape on FUQUA CONSERVATORY Tape above.
    - TV NEWS CLIPS OF ATLANTA, INC. regarding Ground Breaking Fuqua Conservatory Video tape - Collection of two news reports regarding ground breaking of the Fuqua Conservatory, 1987 (Box 117-119)
    - Regarding Fuqua Conservatory 1. Ch 2, Fri. 3-10-89, 8:30pm 'Fresh, Wild & Exotic' Video tape - Copy of program that appeared on Atlanta TV highlighting the new Conservatory (including a short interview with the Fuquas), 1989 (Box 117-119)
      Program on this tape on tape above (see item 438).
    - Four (4) copies of GROUND BREAKING CEREMONIES FOR THE DOROTHY FUQUA CONSERVATORY, ATLANTA BOTANICAL CARDEN, PIEDMONT PART AT THE PRADO, ATLANTA GEORGIA. Video tape - Recording of events/ceremonies surrounding ground breaking for the Fuqua Conservatory (includes very short speech by J.B. Fuqua), 1987 (Box 117-119)
    - Regarding Rotunda Video tape - News announcement of donation of money to botanical garden to build the Dorothy Chapman Fuqua Conservatory, 1986 (Box 117-119)
    - WSB DCF Conservatory Video tape - Home recording, possibly, of program on Atlanta TV highlighting the new Conservatory (including a short interview with the Fuquas) 'Fresh, Wild & Exotic', 1989 (Box 117-119)
      Program on this tape on tape above.
    - June 1, 1987, TV 5 News interview with Dorothy Fuqua about the conservatory Video tape, 1987 (Box 117-119)
    - 'FRESH, WILD AND EXOTIC,' Dorothy Chapman Fuqua Conservatory Atlanta Botanical Garden, WJBF-TV, April 23, 1989 Video tape - Documentary regarding the Conservatory, 1989 (Box 117-119)
      Program on this tape is on tape above (see item 438) with added introduction, program was (re)broadcast on WJBF-TV Augusta GA.
    - PACKAGE OF DOROTHY FUQUA CONSERVATORY, AND INTERVIEW WITH SALLY BROYLES Video tape - Documentary on the Conservatory and plants contained within including with volunteer at the Botanical Garden (Box 117-119)
    - J. B. Fuqua - 4:26 Produced - Tom Budnik Video tape - profile of Fuqua including interview Material (Box 120)
      Also present on other videos.
    - Story of Tom Harken & Miss Melba, Good Morning America Sunday, March 1, 1998 Video tape - Tom Harken, Horatio Algier Award winner, inspirational story, 1998 (Box 120)
      Cursory review shows no direct mention of Fuqua.
    - Jack Segal Video tape - Episode of Kentucky Business Week featuring panel discussion regarding purchase and reopening of Kentucky Electric Steel, 1996? (Box 120)
      Fuqua mentioned as seller of Kentucky Steel Mill.
    - The White House Bicentennial Dinner Video tape - C-SPAN coverage of a Clinton era dinner celebration of the White House, 2000 (Box 120)
    - AMERICAN SEATING HISTORY SHOW Video tape - Promotional program for American Seating (a Fuqua Company?) (Box 120)
      No direct mentions of Fuqua or Fuqua Industries.
    - China - Ball glove Video tape - Home video style tour of several factories and other scenes in China (Box 120)
    - OCT. 8, 1993 FUQUA HOMECOMING - PARADE Video tape - home video style of celebration of anniversary of Fuqua School, 1993 (Box 120)
      Fuqua present and introduced at the celebration.
    - The J. B. Fuqua Foundation Video tape - Cumberland College Promotional program dedicated to the Fuqua Foundation (Box 120)
      Fuqua not mentioned directly, opening credits dedicate program to Fuqua Foundation.
    - The J. B. Fuqua Foundation, Dr. J. B. Fuqua Video tape - Cumberland College Promotional program dedicated to the Fuqua Foundation and J. B. Fuqua himself (Box 120)
      Fuqua not mentioned directly, opening credits dedicate program to Fuqua Foundation and Dr. J.B. Fuqua.
    - Once a Night is Enough, Video tape - On cursory review, tape appears to be blank (Box 120)
    - Without Borders Video tape - TBS-produced program on river populations in different parts of the world, highlighting pollution and other issues (Box 120)
    - Unidentified Video Image Producer, Video tape - SYBERVISION 'Profiles OF Achievement' on Kimmens Wilson (Box 120)
      Duplicate.
    - THE DAY AFTER Video tape - home-made copy of airing of The Day After: post nuclear war TV-movie (Box 120)
    - Tour of Library of Congress Manuscript Division C-SPAN 12/16/99 Video tape - Program of tour of Library of Congress Presidential Collections (Box 120)
    - MICROSOCIETY Video tape - The micro-society school: a real world in miniature: program of the McNeil-Lehrer News Hour Program (Box 120)
    - The Mobil Relationship Video tape - Partners in Excellence: The Mobile Relationship Training video program covering rate of pay, teamwork, objectives and standards, 1992 (Box 120)
      No direct mention of J.B. Fuqua, multiple passing mentions of Fuqua School of Business and Duke athletic teams in video.
    - Eight (8) copies of The Farmville Herald (May 31, 1972) with cover story of J.B. Fuqua giving Graduation speech at Hampden-Sydney College, 1972 (Box 121-123)
    - Seven (7) copies of The Farmville Herald (June 2, 1972) with front page story J.B. Fuqua speech at Hampden-Sydney College, 1972 (Box 121-123)
    - Envelope of assorted newspaper clipping regarding Fuqua family and Lady Bird Johnson visit to Savannah, 1973-1975 (Box 121-123)
    - Envelope of assorted photographs of Fuqua family and J.B. Fuqua, some with LB Johnson (Box 121-123)
      Envelope addressed from the LBJ Ranch, dated May 1978.
    - Last of 1979 and first of 80 Envelope - assorted news clippings, correspondences, photographs, holiday greetings, announcements, publications (Box 121-123)
    - Correspondence from/to a teacher asking for Fuqua's assistance to pay for a guided tour of Europe, 1958 (Box 121-123)
    - Correspondence and contract regarding Bell Music for Prospect Methodist Church, 1967 (Box 121-123)
    - Personal letters (Box 121-123)
      Personal and business correspondences, Fuqua Industries pamphlet, photos, invitation, postcards, clippings, correspondences, automobile registrations, membership cards, and a 1938 certificate of a $90 loan to J.B. Fuqua.
    - Photographs, 1935-1939 (Box 121-123)
    - Duplicate from D.C.F. Scrapbook (Box 121-123)
      News clippings, photos, invitations, funeral and wedding announcements, newsletters, collection of poetry about Augusta, church program.
    - Photographs of J.B. Fuqua, head-shots (Box 121-123)
    - Airplane photographs, 2 photographs (Box 121-123)
    - WJBF-(TV) photograph, 1953? (Box 121-123)
    - Photo of Fuqua's first office chair at WGAC, 1940 (Box 121-123)
    - Photo of J.B. Fuqua in nautical uniform, 1936 (Box 121-123)
    - Picture of Edith Vaughn (Box 121-123)
    - J.B. Fuqua pictures, July 1972 (Box 121-123)
    - 1960-1968 Scrapbook - assorted news clippings, publications, announcements, correspondences, etc, 1960-1968 (Box 121-123)
      Materials divided by pages with years written on them.
    - Clippings
      - Front page of The Miami Herald with photo and story regarding Jackie Gleason and Spiro Agnew playing golf, August 25, 1971 (Box 121-123)
      - Copy of Finance: The Magazine of Money & Business, August 1977 (Box 121-123)
        J.B. Fuqua on cover.
      - Offprints of story about J.B. Fuqua in Finance, 1977 (Box 121-123)
      - Offprint copies of Fighting Off Fuqua Was an Unsettling Victory for Hoover, story in Fortune magazine, October 1979 (Box 121-123)
      - Keeping Christmas (Box 121-123)
        Essay written by J.B. Fuqua in the 7th Grade.
      - Offprint copy of 1965 Year of the Slowdown from Sponsor, January 1965 (Box 121-123)
      - J. B. FUQUA BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION (Box 121-123)
      - J. B. Fuqua resume, 1973 (Box 121-123)
      - Materials related to entry for J. B. Fuqua in Men of Achievement Who's Who, 1974-1975 (Box 121-123)
      - J.B. Fuqua's Grand Design, from Fortune magazine, June 1979, 5 reprint copies (Box 121-123)
      - J.B. Fuqua: Building a Corporate Empire, from the MBA Executive, April 1979, 2 reprint copies (Box 121-123)
      - For J.B. Fuqua, Business Is the Only Recreation, from the Nation's Business, July 1979, 2 reprint copies (Box 121-123)
      - Photocopy of article J. B. Fuqua Gambles, Wins, from the The Charlotte Observer, January 5, 1970 (Box 121-123)
      - Handwritten page with colleges/institutions and amounts written on it (Box 121-123)
      - Photocopy of article Fuqua Plan Makes Big Splash from the The Atlanta Journal and the Atlanta Constitution, June 11, 1972 (Box 121-123)
      - Prospect High School Reunion, August 4, 1973 (Box 121-123)
      - Prospect High School Reunion Program dated August 4, 1973, 1973 (Box 121-123)
      - Page cut out of The Atlanta Constitution (March 15, 1972) containing Elimination of Stockholder Meetings Asked by Fuqua story, 1972 (Box 121-123)
      - End Annual Meetings by J. B. Fuqua from The New York Times, April 23, 1972 (Box 121-123)
      - City TV Station Stock Included in Sale Speculation in Wilmington Morning Star (Box 121-123)
      - Faded fax page of quote from Julius Caesar (Box 121-123)
      - Photocopy of article featuring Fuqua (Box 121-123)
      - Photocopies of Fuqua Looks Toward Far East For 1980s, from The Atlanta Constitution, December 12, 1979 (Box 121-123)
    - Business cards of J.B. Fuqua (Box 121-123)
    - Rolodex (Box 121-123)
    - "My Favorite Cartoons", 1988 (Folder 1)